(This story has been inspired
by true historical events)
(Hwang Jung-min)
(So Ji-sub)
(Song Joong-ki)
(Lee Jung-hyun
Kim Suan)
(Kim Min-jae, Kim Joong-hee,
Kim In-woo, Shin Seunghwan)
(Lee Kyoung-young)
Get down, quickly
Get down there
Move
Keep in line
Hey, we can't fit in here
Someone small, okay?
Kids?
Send the young ones in there
Get in there
Gas!
Help! Help!
Help!
Where are you going! Get back here!
Not today
Get in
Bastard
(November 1944)
(Japan Hashima Coal Mine, Korean Quarters)
I'm sorry
You've had to pay for my generation's sins
I wish you success
Grow old and fight for Korea
We'll come back for you
Don't you worry about an old man like me
Just live a good life
Time is running out
Let's go
Won't you come with us?
Then who will care for Mr. Yoon?
Even the weather is helping you out
It's time. Hurry
Go on! Be careful
If one of you is killed on the way
Leave him or you'll all die
Care only for yourself until
reaching Nomo Peninsula
Hide there for a clay to rest up,
then go to Nagasaki
A lot of people get caught
in Nagasaki as well
So don't rest easy until you reach Korea
Please survive,
and let's meet in a better world
Hurry
Who's there? Don't move!
Stop or we'll shoot!
You want to get killed too?
How much further?
What?
How much further to go?
We're almost there! Keep going!
Yamada-san
Should we fish them out?
Why bother?
Just report that we found them drowned
With three catches, we'll get a bonus
Let's go back, quickly!
1,2,3
(Labor Mobilization for the Japanese Empire)
It's not the front line
Why get so uptight?
It's no joke. I've been drafted
Oh my, drafted?
Don't you intellectuals know that slogan?
"“The people have a duty to the nation"
Then will you send your son to do his duty?
My son has tuberculosis
If not for that
He could serve in the
rear like you, earn money
And support the Greater
East Asia Co-Prosperity...
What's with this damned music?
Would you like a drink?
Mister Lee, Mister Lee
Damn
Are you going to play this music all night?
We're sending boys off to war,
it's too gloomy
Don't you have any nice jazz?
Why?
You know that jazz is banned
You want me arrested?
Who's going to arrest you?
This room is filled with high-ranking,
well-connected people
We need some fun for once
You want some fun?
That'll cost you a bit of hazard pay
Oh gosh... all right
(February 7, 1945 Peninsula Hotel,
Myeongdong Seoul)
Where's Gang-ok?
On the stage
If he wants to stay out of jail,
tell him to come down and find me
Huh, why? Did he make trouble again?
Damn idiot
Fooled around with a section chief's wife
Gang-ok
The tap dance of love
Until the night is gone
Gang-ok
Okay
Give her a hand
No, come on
Come on, everyone
With a glass of champagne
Let's have ourselves a dance
Where's my wife?
Stand UP!
Spin! Spin, you brat
Wait, Daddy! Wait!
Are you out of your mind?
The section chief's wife likes my music
She kept offering to buy dinner,
how can I turn it down?
And offered to introduce
me to the theater owner
All we did was eat
If you get drafted for this,
what will she do?
I'm not going to be drafted
You think you'll get away
with touching a section chief's wife?
Then today you play jazz?
Did you bring it?
Here
It's nine musicians, including you
And your daughter makes ten
There'll be nothing left for me
and my police colleagues
I'm always in your debt, Mr. Sugiyama
Look
I'll arrange a bribe for you and your band
I'm asking around the offices
of Japanese factories
Explain the situation to your band well
And bring in some more cash
You always said you wanted to work in Japan
I heard
(The Philippines) The army was
driven out of the Philippines again
Is Japan going to lose?
That's all just talk.
Don't you read the papers?
There are thousands of U.S.
POWs in Japan now
It'll be over before the
cherry blossoms fall, trust me
We're going to see cherry blossoms?
(February 12, 1945 Ferry to Shimonoseki)
Get off then
Let's go
God, what a smell
You should be sucking on your mom's breasts
What's a kid like you doing on this boat?
I was running errands for my father
And the town clerk said by joining the army
I can earn lots of money
and put me in a truck
Okay, okay
Couldn't even tell my
parents before leaving
Tell me about it.
They dragged me off on my wedding night
As a newlywed?
I was still hard down there
And already forgetting her face
You in the glasses, how'd you end up here?
I go to Keijo University
Whoa!
You are an intellectual?
No doubt, studying is
better than going to war
I heard if you work like crazy for one year,
you get a house?
Even still...
How could they drag off pre-pubescent boys?
Snatching them from the fields
or when they're out wrestling
Give me the case
When the boat lands
we'll ditch these guys
- So bear it until then -Okay
All of you brought cash?
Take it out
This is our lifeline
If we lose this, we're dead
Okay
Dad, where are we really going?
You'll see later. Stop asking me, go away
You asshole
There's a fight
Is that Choi Chil-sung?
The famous gangster?
Stupid Koreans,
making sure everyone knows we like infighting
Can't help but fight each other
Stop fighting! Calm down!
Sohee
Go away! Go!
Any more trouble,
we'll call it a riot and start shooting
What the fuck is he saying?
Hey
Can anyone here speak Jap?
If you freak out again,
they'll start shooting
So shut the fuck up and calm down
How'd your mouth get so filthy?
Is it as filthy between your legs?
Did you ever see between my legs?
Did you?
Do you even know who you're talking to?
Sit down!
You look like gangsters
from some Seoul slum
So if the Japs slap you around
You take it out on Korean girls?
Quiet, sit down
All right, just let go
Sit down, guys
I said sit
Not much worth grabbing there anyway
Are you a man?
I feel bad for your mom...
Wow, she made a fool of him
Stick out too much and people hate you
Sometimes you have to keep your head down
Some people bring on their fate
(Shimonoseki Harbor, Japan)
Dear passengers
The ferry from Busan to
Shimonoseki has arrived
Japanese passengers,
please await separate instructions
Sohee, listen to me
If you lose my hand
Watch my back and follow me
- You guys, hold those cases tight -Okay
Stay focused
Hold this
Sohee! Sohee!
Excuse me
Pardon me
This letter is from Detective Sugiyama
Of Seoul Central Police Station
Where can I find Shimura-san?
Shimura-san?
Yes
Detective Sugiyama from Seoul
Told me to find Shimura-san
There are lots of Shimuras here
This way, please
Hey, take them
Wait...
Detective Sugiyama...
(Recommendation letter)
Wait, let go
He told me to find Shimura
(Workers' ferry to Hashima)
Sohee, are you okay?
Sohee, are you okay? Are...
I don't need that!
Asshole!
Stop it!
Stop!
Daddy!
Sohee! Sohee!
Sohee, it'll be okay!
Stay with those women!
Please stop!
No!
Next!
Take your bag and go!
Move forward
Keep going
Bastard
It really is nothing, you see
I just have cigarettes
What's this?
Give it here
Go, now!
Don't stare. Eyes forward
Hey, shut up and put
your head on the ground
Hands on your head
I said hands on your head
Nothing
I have nothing
Foreheads on the ground
What do we do with these?
It's war here, too
Get rid of that Korean habit
of depending on everyone
Sir! Sir!
You're Korean?
Just a moment, please
There's been some kind of mistake
I was supposed to meet someone here
We haven't been drafted like the others
This is from Detective Sugiyama
at Seoul Central Police Station
And this is our performing license
I'm Lee Gang-ok of the Lee Gang-ok Band
We released a record at Okay Record Company
We performed at
Government Hall, Myungdong Theater
Peninsula Hotel, everywhere!
Musicians?
1, 2, 3,4
This kind of shit always
gets mixed up in the crowd
They said it's a factory.
Why take off our clothes?
Follow me
Go on
Are those tattoos?
Here at Hashima Comfort Station
We've received a special medal for
being free of venereal disease
To protect our perfect record
please keep yourselves clean
Next
Sir, just a minute
This is a luxury Western watch called Rolex
It was a gift from someone
at the Governor-General's office
I'm sure you'll take care of things
But I came here with my daughter
Lee Sohee. We came off the boat separately
She's just a little girl
If you could even tell me where she is...
Can you play
"Cherry Blossoms of the Same Class"?
Yes
Damned music men are
settling in comfortably
Son of a bitch
You and I are
Cherry blossoms of the same class
Blooming in the same
Naval training ground
Any flower
Is destined to fall
So let us fall brilliantly
For the sake of our nation
I see some talented men
from Korea have arrived
Welcome
Yes
Thank you
I am from Seoul...
Sorry... Sorry
I am the manager of Hashima Mine
Shimazaki Daisuke
We welcome you from distant Korea
To fulfill your duty here
As loyal subjects of
His Majesty the Emperor
I grant you the honor of taking part
in the Imperial Army's war
Here at Hashima Mine
For 50 years,
this place has led as a supplier of coal
To the industry of the
Great Japanese Empire
This is a historic site
The coal we produce here is not merely coal
A single lump of coal
is a drop of blood
A weapon
And a piece of history
Sons of the Emperor
I urge you to fulfill your duties
As glorious soldiers of industry
And to not dishonor the
Imperial Japanese Army
Hurry up!
(Japanese Residential Area Comfort Station)
- How dare you Japanese...
- Go away
- Sister.
- Filthy whore!
Shame on you
Don't get pregnant at the comfort station
One woman got pregnant
at the Chinese station
They cut her stomach and took the baby out
And a few clays later she was
receiving soldiers again
We will now assign dormitories
After locating your room
Prepare quickly and gather outside
The account slips we give you
Show the transport fees you
incurred while coming here
Traveling costs from Seoul
and other cities to Busan
The ferry to Shimonoseki
And transport to Hashima Island,
have been covered by the company
(Korean Living Quarters)
And will be deducted from your pay
Housing costs provided by the company
will be deducted from your pay
All personal items supplied to you
are covered by the company
and will be deducted from
your first month's pay
All expenses for meals
are covered by the company
and will be deducted from your pay
Hey, get up if you're done eating
For the country's future and your future
National bond and savings fees
Health insurance and pension funds
are calculated in a lump sum
And will be deducted from your pay
(Insurance Card Savings account)
For the sake of those
who don't speak our language
we employ translators
and provide job training
Various amenities
and necessary equipment are furnished
All these items
will be deducted from your pay
If your first month's pay
is less than the company's expenses
Fees will be deducted from your next pay
What the hell will we have left?
I'll just run up debts here
Hey, get moving
Consider today a workplace tour
to learn your duties
We at Hashima Mine
Do not underestimate you for being Koreans
We believe you can excel from the first day
Stop! Masks on!
Put your mask on, damn it
Masks on
Shit, can't you walk? You praying?
Get up now!
My fucking glasses broke!
Your glasses broke, so you're talking back?
Are you? Are you?
Stop it, you asshole
Just give him a break on
bath time and meal time
He's just a kid
Step aside
What are you doing?
Everyone sit down!
Fucking hell
Hey music man!
You speak Jap, right?
Get over here
Translate for me
I'm ready to kick that Yakuza wannabe's ass
Translate, now
I request to duel that Korean boss of yours
I'm that famous Seoul
gangster Choi Chil-sung
I came here to beat your Korean Yakuza boss
I am Choi Chil-sung
I'm here to challenge
that Korean labor boss
We fight samurai style, and if I win
Me and my boys will watch over the Koreans
My boys and I will oversee the Koreans
If I lose, I'll treat him as my boss
If I lose, that Korean boss will be my boss
You assholes
That was a swear word
Think you're a circus ringleader?
Drag him off!
Wait
That sounds like fun
All you need to do is win
There are new Korean girls
at the comfort station
How about betting on a pass?
Comfort station?
Everyone stop!
Koreans fighting each other
is just what they want
The more we fight
The more we play into their hands
This bastard isn't Korean
like the rest of us
What are you looking at, you stupid Koreans
From now on
I'll be leading the Koreans
If you back me,
I'll keep the Koreans in line
Please support me
See me at the labor office
Hurrah for Choi Chil-sung!
And where did this freak come from?
Boss!
Let's whistle for him,
new boss Choi Chil-sung
Everyone bow
The beauties have arrived
Everyone take a seat
Sit
Go ahead, sit
Hurry
Here
This meal is to welcome you
Why so melancholy?
You, who will give up your bodies
to our soldiers fighting
in the Great East Asian War
And to our soldiers of industry
are indeed invaluable assets
Take pride in yourselves
We used to employ first-class geisha
or former actresses from film studios
Now mostly Korean women work here
But this innocence is part of their charm
This mood is too heavy
for a feast of welcome
Play that record I brought
Yes, sir
To help you feel comfortable
I brought a Korean record which I enjoy
It's quite lively
We prepared beds for you here
So relax, listen to some music
And get to bed early tonight
Sister, this song...
This is me singing
This song...
I sang this song
Hey! What are you doing?
Give it back
Tell them I used to sing this song
Tell them I sang it, please
Tell them
She sang what's playing right now
I can sing and dance,
play instruments, whatever
I can clean and do laundry
She can perform, play instruments
and is also good at housework
Ask her what she did before
He asked what you did in Korea
I played music in Seoul. The Yamamura Band
She performed at the Yamamura Band
My father and the rest of the band
are all here
Long live the Emperor
Hurrah
(July 1945, OSS Training Camp)
(Korean Liberation Army in China)
How is your training with the OSS soldiers?
I'm trying my best
You've got higher marks than the Americans
The Seoul infiltration operation
you've been planning
I'm sorry,
but we need you for something else
Some OSS intelligence
was leaked to our side
The U.S. has developed a new bomb
They say its power is beyond imagination
The blast radius is up to 200km
If they drop that
from a B-29 onto the Japanese mainland...
That's all unconfirmed talk for now
The point is,
the Soviets are about to invade
The U.S. has already taken Okinawa
If the Soviets join in
Japan won't last long
It's time to focus on winning the war
Not the battle
For a speedy liberation,
we must join together
Yoon Hak-chul
Only he can resolve the conflicts
Between all the factions
fighting for Korean independence
He handled fundraising at the KPG
But two years ago,
he was caught by the Japanese
And disappeared without a trace
We assumed he was executed without trial
But according to U.S. intel,
he was detained near Nagasaki
At Hashima Coal Mine
Go bring back Mr. Yoon
(We will always be together. Our Hashima)
Gather around, everyone
If we screw up again,
we'll be back in the mines
Do your best! And smile!
If you don't smile I'll have Chil-sung
take you back to the mine
Get ready, quick
Hey, why don't you eat that?
Raw eggs are gross
Eat when I tell you, kid!
It's great for your throat
Some people can't eat at all!
Hurry UP
Hey!
Abracadabra... ta-dah!
Look at that grin
If you want food, you have to pay for it
Newbies who arrived today,
just follow the man in front
Fuckers don't feed us crap.
The fuck is he blabbering about?
Isn't that dynamite?
What'll you do with it?
Stop sputtering and be quiet
The liquid that seeps out is sweet
Need to eat at least that to survive
What if your stomach explodes?
Give me a taste
Help me here
It's okay
It's just the coal dust in my lungs
That's why I cough out black sputum
Sir, are you okay?
I'm fine
Hey, there's gas coming out
SO what?
Block off the gas! And pump out sea water
At the center of Japan's leadership
In the Great East Asian War is
Hashima Coal Mine
Long live the Emperor
Long live the Japanese Empire
For Hashima Mine
And its executives returning
to the head office
Cheers
Rock, scissors, paper! Rock! Rock!
We're even, try again
Here, it's your turn
Didn't you eat!
Are you alright?
Support his back
Are you hurt?
It's sliding down!
Hey kid, out of the way
No!
Huh?
What's that noise?
Run!
Run out quick! Bring your tools
Don't drop your tools, bring them
Thank you
Thank you very much
How many times has Mine No. 2 caught fire?
Do I need to step in
every time this happens?
What about the passage to Mine No.3?
It hasn't spread there yet
How much is Mine 2 producing?
It has the lowest production
We're already 1100 meters
below the seafloor
So it'll be hard to mine deeper
Save me
Save the young ones first
Mr. Yoon! You must go up
Don't let anyone die! Not one!
No
That's the Korean section, right?
Seal them off
Prevent damage spreading to other mines
There are people here! You bastards!
There are people here!
Sir, Yoon Hak-chul is in the mine
Out of the way
I told you not to put him in the mine
If he dies
What should we do if the Koreans riot?
By whatever means necessary, get him out
Hold on just a bit
Hurry up and dig
Are you going to work all day? Huh?
They're waiting for you
Jong-go! There's a problem in Mine 2
Damn, I worked all night!
Why'd they have to wake me up?
Isn't that where we plugged
the gas leak before?
Hey, just shut your mouth and follow orders
Ah, are you back on duty?
Fuck
You sure this connects to Mine 3?
Shouldn't you know that?
What? You prick!
Blast through it
What?
There's no other way
We point the gas at these supports
And light it
Newbie! Shut the fuck up!
I don't know if there's enough gas
to explode thoroughly
You know...
I hid this thing here
We can't drill any deeper
We can't
Gas keeps leaking, what if there's a fire?
That's why we called you technicians!
Okay, okay...
It's going in!
Keep drilling!
Pull
Pull it
The Koreans heard there was an accident
But they don't know yet who lived or died
Announce we'll move wounded Koreans
to a main hospital in Nagasaki
Then send them to the crematorium
And burn them with the corpses
There are limits to how
many Koreans we can bring
Given the war struggles
We will not allow the company
to lose any more money
I'll be sure to contain the problem
Chiba -san
When do you plan to inspect our mine?
- The thing is...
- I'm sorry
As I'm grateful
for your recommendation of our facility
I mean to send someone to
express my deepest gratitude
I see
You won't be disappointed
Where is Yoon Hak-chul now?
He's coming! He's coming!
Here he comes!
If the company doesn't
release a list of casualties
And draw up compensation and safety plans
I will refuse all talks
with Manager Shimazaki
We support you!
We support you! We support you!
It's about time to leave
Wait a minute! You give me this
You're in charge of toilets now
You'll scoop piss and shit
Hey!
Fuck“.
Someone tell this madman not to hit me
Give me my money's worth
I don't need
any Korean bitches glaring at me
Come on, don't be like this
You got trained by the American
But without their help
You think you can escort Mr.
Yoon out of here?
The plan was to use the network here
And contact Korean agents
at OSS headquarters
Through an agent planted
on the food ship that stops here
We'll go by ship to the U.S.
base in Okinawa
How do we know you're not on their side?
You say you're OSS-trained resistance?
I was a student soldier
Sent to Japanese unit 7991 in China
Then I escaped last July in Xuzhou,
then this February
I met KLA General Lee
Beom-seok in Chongqing
Did he send any personal message to me?
He says he'll treat you to
your favorite trotter stew
And cold dishes at Hwapyung Restaurant
When do you plan to move?
I'll send in another girl
Just sit
I said sit! I'm not here for romance
Why not?
Do the marks on my chest make you go limp?
Hell...
Don't you need a Korean to complain to,
to breathe easier?
Fuck... even worse than the Japs
Are these damned mosquitos
At first I was dragged to China
I had no idea
They said I was going to work
They drove me
To a Japanese army base
Hell
The mosquitos bit me like crazy
Some mosquito bites can kill a person
One bite, and your whole
body swells with fever
However much you drink, your insides burn
There was a girl from Heungyang
The Japanese said she was
pretending to be sick
Put her on nails and
rolled her back and forth
She died in front of everyone
I didn't want to end up like her
I was too scared to tell them I was sick
Figured I'd rather die fast, so I drank lye
But I didn't die
It was a Japanese doctor
who stopped me from dying
But then a Korean pimp washed me
And threw me right back
at those Japanese guys
It was a fucking Korean town clerk
who sent me to that comfort station
When the unit retreated, I barely escaped
But that Korean pimp
caught and sent me here
So I need a Korean to complain to?
To breathe easier?
Biting the hand that feeds you
You need to control your temper
Sooner or later, things will get better
Fuck
Are you doing a lousy job on purpose?
Try finding any guy who
won't get off on this
Dragging me out of the hospital to do this
Okay, here
I send out so many of these,
why does so little come back?
Damned guards cut the rations
You're not hoarding it yourself?
Shit...
Bro, just one cigarette
You still didn't pay for last month's
Fuck
The damned Japanese raised their
pension funds or whatever
We all had them raised
So control your gambling! If you're broke,
just sleep
Wait, pay up before you go
Damn it
Give this to the attendant
for 10 cigarettes
Yes, sir
Manager Shimazaki is calling you
Sohee!
What is it? Oh no...
A splinter
Be more careful, kid
What's that smell?
I've been thinking of this for a while
After today's accident
I thought I should meet you
And propose something
Before it's too late
I see
About your daughter...
In the recent U.S. bombing
of our head office
Chiba-san lost his daughter
Rather than having her stay here
Where it's so dangerous
I was thinking
To send her to Chiba-san
as an adopted daughter
Mr. Lee
We're in a war
In wartime, winners don't always survive
Survivors are true winners
On the next freight ship out
Let's send Sohee
Huh?
Meeting in this world of woe
What is your wish?
Will being rich
Make you happy?
Airplane
The post office key?
We'll pay whatever you want
Hell, how would you know what I want?
We'll give you this in advance
Wow, advance pay?
I need to know what this is about
We need to check a package
I don't team up with
people who keep secrets
If you need to check a package
Isn't it easier to just bribe one
of the labor officers?
Well...
we need the telegraph
The telegraph?
I'm going on patrol, how about you guys?
Know how to use it?
Just get us the key
A newbie wants to use the telegraph
A Korean who looks like
an independence leader
Bribes me...
What's going on here?
Forget it, then
- I already know, how can I forget?
- Geeze
Should I go ask the boss to look into this?
Park Mu-young
Mr. Yoon will escape from here
All we need is the key, no trouble
You decide
If you don't cooperate
We'll kill you
Hey, Yamamura!
What are you doing? It's almost curfew
Where have you been?
I've been looking for you
The drawings are done
Tell Maeda to see me tomorrow
What, already?
I want one, too
But what are you doing here?
They're fighting over gambling debts
I'm trying to mediate
Damn idiots
Shake hands
I'll take care of this, you go on
All right, then
Have a good night
You don't need to pay
But I have one condition
When he escapes
Take me and my daughter
What are you talking about
I take it that old man won't be swimming?
Since you want the telegraph,
you must have something lined up
Just kill me
Or have the Japanese kill you
Or take my daughter and me
This time, you decide
If our plan is leaked
I'll kill you myself
One, two, three
Where the hell did he go?
Can't he leave me alone?
Hey, go to my spot
Hey painter
Where's the guy who made
me a lock that time?
Is he on the night shift?
Why don't I see him?
Bang!
They sent him to the tool repair factory...
To work as a technician,
since he's good with tools
Bang!
Tool repair factory? Shit
Good afternoon
I need a favor from the locksmith
Go ahead
What brings you out here?
You want another lock?
No, I've got a really important key
I'm scared of losing it, so I'd like a copy
Hand it over
Yes but... I need to bring it back
Something smells fishy
How come you get all the luck?
Which woman's home?
You're quick
Her husband carries the key around
You know how it is
Here you go. See you later
Hello!
We'd still be nice to
Sohee without these gifts
I know, but treat her well
What are you sighing about?
Come here
I talked to your supervisor lady
You'll move to her room
So when I call you at night
You can run out quickly
Can't you ask the manager
to let us stay together?
Why? Did he do something?
It's just that I'm lonely here...
The other women tell me I'm annoying
Even when the manager takes care of me
Damn bitches
That's why I told you
to behave well with other people
And be careful what impression you give
What are you crying about?
Don't you know all that I'm doing for you?
Think you're the only
one who's got it hard?
Why do you always say
everything's my fault?
Never mind. What do I say to you?
Anyway...
Always be ready
So you can run right out if I call you
Then we can be together, all right?
Got a good movie for us?
Yes, a love story!
Good evening
Bro
Want to see a dirty picture?
Uh good!
Come this way
The outside door,
the office and the director's room
You remember my terms?
I have eyes everywhere, you know
Hey, boss!
What is it now?
Nothing, I want to show you something
What the hell? It won't open?
Gang-ck, that rat!
Hey, assholes!
Who is it? Stop right there
(Hashima Eagle contacted)
(Preparations to transport Eagle complete)
(Number of passengers?)
(Yoon and Park, two people)
(Sending food transport
ship in 48 hrs, 5AM)
(Find Takagura on transport ship)
(Wishing safe return, end)
(Korean Account Records)
Seems the war is going badly
When was the last time
Japan used good paper like this?
What do propaganda pamphlets
have to do with the war?
The U.S. still has enough money
To make pamphlets with good paper
Aren't wars ultimately won
by those with the most money?
Give me the relevant documents
for me and the other Koreans
Ah...
More leaflets littering our island
Those are bombers
Citizens and employees
Turn off lights and stay indoors
I repeat
Citizens and employees
Turn off lights and stay indoors
I repeat...
It's time
Why so cheap this time?
Too many people involved now,
I want to wrap it up
Where's the attendant?
Let's go
Damn those bastards!
Sir, it's time for your medicine
Sir?
Quiet around here
Sohee!
Sohee“.
What is it?
Gang-ok? Come on in
All right. Where's Sohee?
Quick...
Let me see Sohee
I'll come back for you
Shit
When did you last see Park?
What?
Mr. Yoon is missing
I couldn't say goodbye to anyone
What kind of operation is this?
I had to keep everything completely secret
And I have something to ask you first
I found Koreans' pay records
(Korean Account Records)
In the post office safe
The pensions and bond payments
taken from their paychecks
Don't go to their accounts
But to someone else's
Your name is entered on their contracts
And half the money flowing
into your account
Is forwarded into Manager
Shimazaki's account
Are you aware of this?
Since coming here
I heard that pay is embezzled
By the manager and several others...
But an account in my name?
Even dead workers'
compensation is going in there
Without their families
being told of their deaths
Shimazaki...
I never thought he'd go this far
Looking through the documents,
I kept seeing your signature
Who could have made those files?
Didn't it occur to you
that Shimazaki could've made it?
No labor strike
or escape plan has ever succeeded here
I wonder why
If you set up a leader of the Koreans
And then use him
Then this kind of control is possible
Can you explain how a man caught
Delivering huge sums for the KLA
Could have received no
trial from the Japanese
And ended up here?
This is just what Shimazaki wanted
Should I answer for you?
You fool!
Shimazaki knew someone like you was coming
You converted
If you weren't on their side,
you'd be in jail
Park Mu-young
No one will follow you once they find out
Why do you think
Shimazaki agreed to negotiate
over their protection?
Why?
Negotiate?
So dragging little boys off
to mines and stealing their money
Was a negotiation?
If you're so convinced of my guilt
Then right here
Shoot me
You scoundrel!
Trying to run off without us?
I warned you!
That if you betray me, I'll report you!
You stay there!
Gang-ok!
Listen closely to me
This is an American spy
with no connection to Korea
If you report him
The two of you can escape
If Shimazaki finds out, you all die!
What was your real goal in coming here?
Sohee!
When I shout
Run to Manager Shimazaki
and tell him everything
He's on Shimazaki's side
God damn fuckers!
Then when does the ship come?
Daddy
Sohee, it's okay. Just stay still
Why do you take the girl!
Let go of her
Drop the gun first
Sir, are you okay?
I'm fine, go watch over our men
Park has betrayed us!
Put down the gun, now
Our men are on the way
Stop being stupid
Try reading this
What kind of plot is this?
Shut up, you scoundrel!
Coming to save someone like you...
Don't you feel sorry for them?
Ito Takamichi Yoon Hak-chul...
I will report your treason
to the Provisional Government of Korea
You bastard!
Run, quick!
This way, quick
This way
Hurry
You Koreans, wait there
Block the Koreans
I'm Japanese
Only Japanese can...
Shut the gate! Get in, quick!
Move aside
Shut the gate
Asshole
What the hell, why are they shooting
Open the gate
Sook, get UP!
You want to die?
Let me go
Sook!
Stop
Don't move
Don't shoot
I'm Ito...
Yoon Hak-chul
Sir
Sir, are you okay?
I'm fine
Are you hurt?
How are you?
I'm okay. Let's get away from here
About that account book...
Don't worry about that.
I'll go back and get it
Did you see what was in it?
Sir, I believe you to the end
Help!
That man, he shot...
Quiet
Sir, are you all right?
Sir, what will we do?
How could this happen to us?
You there! Did Gang-ok die too?
Someone thought they saw his corpse
So we're looking...
Gang-ok, where are you?
Damn it
Daddy, I'm thirsty
Why are you giving me that?
- Any food here?
- Probably
Drive out the Koreans!
Does the line work?
Hold out as long as you can
with the food and water you have
Our manager's unrecoverable
Are you telling us to just die?
Yesterday the U.S. dropped
a new bomb on Hiroshima
A new bomb?
Word is coming in
that it's tremendously powerful
There's no official report yet
But it's said there are 100,000 casualties
And no living thing survived
The Americans have created
something unimaginable
Are we going to lose this war?
After Hitler's death and
the fall of Germany
Industrialists who helped the Nazis
Are being lined up and
tried as war criminals
If you have any materials
that can be used against us
Burn them
If it's a war crimes trial
Shouldn't we kill the Koreans
who could testify against us?
That'd be the most effective solution
But with Shimazaki in that state
Can it be done?
If you take care of things properly
Then surely you can take his place
Drive out the Koreans!
Drive them out!
You little prick
You ruined everything!
Does it hurt a lot?
I can't believe this
Corpses will be burned to prevent disease
So finish identifying the bodies
What about Japanese corpses?
Why is it only us who are
burned like garbage?
So as not to create more panic
For now, only you and I
must know of the manager's death
Take this for now
I couldn't find what you described
So I just took anything
I hear a Japanese schoolgirl was murdered
Korean attendant Song
Jong-go says he saw it
And the suspect is Korean
That's good news
Now we have a justification
to crack down on the Koreans
Hey!
Sohee!
Bro, you're alive?
You think I'm dead?
Why'd you want to meet here
And not the kitchen?
There's someone who can't know
the two of us are alive
Have this
What the hell? Eat this?
Hey, take a can from my shelf
It disappeared in the bombing
Huh? What about the cash?
All of it?
God damn it
It was a life-or-death situation
Why didn't you get it? Where have you been?
It's a long story
Is Yoon asking about me?
Until the situation stabilizes
I will carry out the duties
of our wounded manager
During this vicious American attack
When everyone is heartbroken
An innocent, pretty young girl
Lost her life to a savage who
couldn't control his lust
Can you see this innocent victim's family?
If you've any conscience, come forward!
What evidence do you
have that it was a Korean?
Witness, come forward
Identify the suspect
He was with us yesterday
You scumbag!
Don't overdo it, you thug
Ah, I want some cold soy noodles
With savory broth... salt on top
I like it better with sugar
All right, sugar it is
Pull out a mouthful of those noodles...
With radish kimchi on the side...
Oh, let's stop this
Only makes me hungrier
When we get out of here
Let's go eat noodles first
Then, we'll go back home?
Of course
That's why your dad is helping me
But right now...
There's something I need
you to help me with
Will you help me?
Mr. Yoon
If you get a chance to leave this island,
you'll take it?
If I take you to the U.S. occupied zone
Can you tell them
I helped you to look after the laborers
And supported Korean liberation?
If the manager is dead
You'll probably get his position
Is that really necessary?
I've thought it over
And we're both smart enough to know
How this war will end
In return for getting you out
Give me the money you
pocketed with the manager
Can I leave right away?
The coal transport ship is almost repaired
Our communications are back
And it's no problem to leave here with you
But if I want to take
my family from Nagasaki
I'll have to follow the
head office's command
And deal with all the Koreans
Deal with?
The Koreans who remembers
what happened here
Must be killed
Where did that old man Yoon hide it?
(Records of Korean laborers)
Hey!
You lost your position as the Korean leader
And took out your grudge
against a Japanese girl
But she fought back
And you strangled her
Is that so hard to admit?
Hey! Just say it's true
and sign with your thumbprint
Then I'll treat you like my older brother
Song Jong-go...
I will fold you like a blanket
And chop you into pieces, you prick
Gather all the remaining dynamite
Tomorrow we'll put all
the Koreans in the mine
Tomorrow morning...
Yamada plans to force all the Koreans
into the mine and kill us
Women of course, and even children
I beg you
I won't ask for myself
But please take Sohee away from here
Surely you can manage to take her
I'm going to escape
With all the Koreans here
In this place where we sweated and toiled
We have a right to proper treatment
Today's arrest of Choi
Chil-sung as a murder suspect
Is no different from what
All us Koreans have suffered!
Therefore, I
Requested Manager Shimazaki
To stop Koreans from being unfairly accused
And demanded an open trial
- Out of the way -Let's go
And furthermore
I will reach an agreement with the manager
First
We will be given the same quality food
as the Japanese
Second
The coal quotas raised last month
Will be lowered
Third
Full time off on holidays
Fourth
Work to repair the island
will be compensated
And finally!
Injured young workers will all be returned
To our homeland Korea
We'll send them home
There's just one condition
Given what we will receive
We need to show our sincerity
Tomorrow is Hashima Mine's first opening
Since the bombing
The manager has asked
As a show of our unity and for a new start
That all Koreans including
women and children
Join the opening ceremony inside the mine
What do you all think?
I Object!
- Huh?
- Who is he?
Yoon Hak-chul never met the manager today
The manager is dead
If you enter the mine tomorrow
Acting manager Yamada will have you buried
What?
Park Mu-young, stop trying to stir chaos
The U.S. has invaded Okinawa
And the war is almost over
Yoon Hak-chul and Yamada
plan to bury you here
And then escape to the U.S. army
Friends!
That man is a spy trying to
divide us Koreans! A spy!
All of you here
Are decisive witnesses
of Hashima's war crimes
Therefore, this company
Plans to bury you in the
mine to destroy all evidence
People!
Tell me!
Who do you trust?
You fucker!
That old geezer is a real fox
Listen up, everyone
Park is an independence fighter
who came to rescue Yoon
But... if you can believe it
Park discovered that
Yoon was Shimazaki's informant
So Yoon shot him with a gun!
And this here!
Written by Yoon and the manager
Lists all of the money
they skimmed off your paychecks
People who died of
accidents, hunger, sickness, violence
People who died trying to escape.
You stole their compensation
This man Lee Gang-ok
To kiss up to the Japanese
Sold his own daughter
And that spy
Is completely unknown to us,
coming from who knows where
That's right
How do we know
Gang-ok and that newbie aren't spies?
Calm down
All of us need to band together
Let's keep our heads and not be fooled
These unknown guys coming in
and slandering our Mr. Yoon
I saw it too
Put down the gun, now!
Our men are on the way
I saw it
I saw you shoot him and Choong-ho too
Jang-woo, have you been bought off too?
Why betray your own country?
Do you really have to sell me?
Stop it, Jang-woo! How could you do it too?
What if I show you this?
4088 Yoon Hak-chul
Torn off your shirt by Choong-ho as he died
Don't be fooled by appearances
They're deceiving you
I saw it too! He's a bad man
That girl saw such an awful thing?
First, let's look at those documents
This is nuts
You need to prove what they say isn't true
Ito Takamichi, Yoon Hak-chul
That money you worked for
Is dirty Japanese money
Guilty of treason
That money was for Korean independence
Was that so wrong?
Bleeding the people dry!
It was for us!
Pretending to lead and deceiving the people
You fools
For betraying the nation
You think killing me will bring liberation?
I punish you in the name of Korea!
I'm the one who gave you
guys all everything
So what are we going to do?
No one's ever managed to escape here
Think we can all just hold hands and leave?
Yoon has always tipped off the manager
That's why they failed
If we take the coal transport
ship in the harbor
We can succeed
Wait a minute
Who's going to drive that big ship?
Hold on, we got a few boatmen here
I've sailed fishing boats
I know the route,
so with 5 or 6 men to row...
Hold on
That freight ship is not a fishing boat
It's not just that, if we all run for it
Won't they start shooting
and stabbing us? What then?
The guards who come to Hashima
Were all judged unfit for the battlefield
And after the bombing
They're still spooked
There are much more of us
And we got military training...
Instead
How about we try negotiating
with the Japanese?
To be honest,
Japanese are more enlightened than us
If we try dialogue...
Dialogue my ass!
If they were sensible,
would we be living this way?
Remember the Kanto Earthquake?
They spread rumors that
Koreans poisoned the wells
How could they say such
a thing and treat us like crap
You say that because you
have skills and lived easy
Who says I lived easy?
You're just trying to divide us, painter!
Hey!
Just decide who'd leave or stay
This is wasting time
He's right
Those who want to go, can go
Those who will stay, stay
You really think
they'd kill so many people?
- Right?
- Yeah!
Daddy, aren't we going?
Damn it, I'm going to blow my top
You stupid Koreans!
If you made it this far,
shouldn't you try to live?
Have you all grown
so used to being stepped on?
My goodness
This girl and I want to live
We'll go ourselves
Wait! I'll go too
I lost my leg and became a cripple
But I won't let them bury me here
But Mallyon,
what if they really kill us all?
Even if just one of us survives, we win
Just one
My life was ruined
But I won't die in their hands
Wait
I'll go too
Are you really staying?
How can you trust them?
You should think it over
Come on, we'll try talking to the Japanese!
Let's go!
There's no time,
so we won't try to persuade you
Are you crazy? What's going on?
You telling them of our
plan is only trouble
So please understand
And besides
It'd be best if they found you tied up
Don't need this
Stabbing me first then
apologizing is useless
Careful, careful...
Wait, I don't see Choi Chil-sung's gang
If they tell the labor attendant...
They said they're going to rescue Choi
Huh?
What'll they do then?
Let's hurry
BOSS
What are you doing here
They say they'll try YOU
Let's go before things get worse
Think of this as a drill, like in training
We're going to move in groups
When we're ready
Women, the wounded
And children will move first at our sign
Our final goal
Is to cross the coal belt over the wall
Board the ship and escape
This is dynamite they prepared for the mine
Explosives team,
tie them to the lantern batteries
It will strengthen the blast
The wounded, use tatami
mats to make shields
Mallyon and the women
will make rope from fundoshi underwear
Weapons team,
take tools and oil from the tool factory
Lee and his band will gather
bottles for bottle bombs
Those who can steer the ship,
help me take control
The rest of you, wait for our signal
It's dangerous, don't touch
Why do you always yell at me?
Why are you here?
If you're ready, I'll bring everyone
Don't do this, come with us
You really think 400 people
can sneak onto a ship?
With all those wounded people?
Then do you want to start a war here?
We'll all die tomorrow anyway
If you try to kill Jong-go, you'll die too!
Hey
Did Park go without finishing them off?
They weren't here before
Damn it
Who's there?
It's me!
Shishido, it's me
Gang-ok
Why are you out so late? Go back inside
I can't believe it either
Get over here, quick
With the big event tomorrow
Yamada said to bring the girls
and pour everyone a drink
Since you guys have it hardest
I brought some girls...
you know?
Really?
Where's the alcohol from?
Shimazaki had it stashed away
And Yamada took it out
Just one drink for each of you
If it's just one, better not to have any
We'll give it a taste
Come this way
Bro! Quickly!
Women and the wounded first
Can we really do this?
I don't see any guards
I spent so much on Korean girls
If the manager finds out he'll be mad
Who will know we started the fire?
They'll think the Koreans
kicked over a candle
While they were sleeping
Out of the way
Go back
Hey, it's women and the wounded first
I'm wounded too
And she's a young girl
Shouldn't we board first?
Bro! Don't you have any shame?
Take a look at these people!
Damn it
Then at least let Sohee go first
No!
Go
Get up there, kid
The sun will be up soon
If you see a cripple go,
you can follow, right?
You'll be fine if you follow me
So you come next
Doong-ge, Doong-ge, Doong-ge
My baby Doong-gem
I am afraid of him being caught
Don't cry, Doong-ge
Will he ride in on the wind?
Will he ride in on the clouds?
Come without a sound
Come without a trace
We wanted to be together
We wanted to live as one
If not in this world
I'll meet you in the next world
Doong-ge, Doong-ge, Doong-ge
My baby Doong-gem
I am afraid of him being caught
Don't cry, Doong-ge
Get to the coal depository
The Koreans are escaping
They've been spotted
I'll join you, so you go first
I keep my promises
As they board the ship
We'll watch their backs
You guys in the front, move
The Koreans started a fire!
The Koreans are escaping!
There! Over there!
Check the back! Quickly!
Don't move in the back
Snipers! Explosives!
Hold on
It's a real war
Kill every last one of them
You rotten bastards
Sohee, stay right here
Kill every one of them
- Stop shooting!
- That way!
Fuck, just let us go home
I said this would never work!
From the very start!
Sohee! Hide, quickly!
Go back, you
Lift! With all your strength!
Go over the wall and into the water
Snipers and explosive team, move!
The rest of you, lift
Light them here
Let's fight to death!
1,2,3
Dae-yeop
Lift it
Sohee, hide here
Follow me, guys
Bring this
Help me
Spread it out
Th row!
Grab the rope and follow me
Bullets! I'm out of bullets!
Bayonets!
Charge!
Bastards! We don't deserve this!
Daddy!
Get back there Sohee, it's dangerous!
Pull the rope
1, 2, 3...
Pull out
Chil-sung, you asshole!
Come back here, bastard!
Pull it back, quick!
Pull it back!
What are you holding back for?
Move!
Pull the rope!
Pull!
Now push it!
A little more!
Lift it up!
Push!
That's it!
Climb up
Everyone climb up
Let the wounded climb up
Sohee, where are you?
Daddy
Sohee
Hey
Come on guys!
Get up!
Bastard!
Sorry for not keeping my promise
You can rest now
I'm on your side!
Kill all the Koreans,
whatever side they're on!
Kill them all
- Bro! What do we do?
- Keep climbing
Sung-il!
Lee Gang-ok
Sohee, stay there!
Stay there
Daddy! Daddy!
I've got you now
Dirty Koreans!
Why aren't you grateful?
Why!
It's all over now
Your manager and Yamada are dead
Now we're going back to our home!
Daddy“.
Boss...
I'm not going to die
Why are you crying?
Stop!
Go over there, Sohee
I'm older, so let me ask you a favor
Give her some soy noodles with sugar
That's what she likes best
Please look after my girl
Sorry I couldn't give you anything
Don't turn your nose up at raw eggs
Sing a song for me
Daddy, Daddy!
Daddy!
You said you wouldn't die!
You promised!
Daddy!
(August 9, 1945, 11:02 AM Nagasaki)
Oh my gosh... look at that
A lot of Koreans live there too
(Hashima's coal mine opened in September 1890)
(From the 1937 invasion of China
to the end of World War II)
(It contributed greatly
to Japan's military industrial sector)
(In the 1970s Japan adopted new energy policies)
(And closed the mine in January 1974)
Sohee
Look at me, girl
(Battleship Island,
as a part of Japan's Meiji Industrial Revolution)
(Battleship Island, as a part of Japan's
Meiji Industrial Revolution) Don't Laugh!
(Became a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 2015)
Don't be nervous
(One of UNESCO's conditions is by
the end of December 2017) Answer me
(One of UNESCO's conditions is by the
end of December 2017) Round your lips
(But Japan has yet to comply)
With confidence
Just like before
(To post notices about forced labor and other
historical facts) Did my little girl prepare well?
(To post notices about forced labor
and other historical facts) Answer me
Ready
2,3
Meeting in this world of woe
What is your wish?
Will being rich
Make you happy?
Under the clear blue sky
Hundreds of thoughts on your mind
Everything is just a dream
Dreaming
Meeting in this world of woe
What is your wish?
Will being rich
Make you happy?
Exaggerated laughter and chatters
Indulging in lust
Letting everything go
Will that make you happy?